<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Tom Nicolosi's Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Simple blog built with Gatsby.]]></description><link>https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 03:55:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[10 Day Challenge]]></title><description><![CDATA[The challenge is simple: Build 10 sites in 10 days. Ten in ten. Why do this? Probably because I am crazy! There is no direct short term gain…]]></description><link>https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog//The Challenge/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog//The Challenge/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 00:24:40 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The challenge is simple: Build 10 sites in 10 days. Ten in ten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do this? Probably because I am crazy! There is no direct short term gain to be had from this other than the momentum it builds and the extra weight that is added to my current portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My portfolio is light because most of my recent efforts have been expended working for other people as part of a team. In that sense I can point to &lt;a href=&quot;http://teeehn.github.io/work/&quot;&gt;my work as a whole&lt;/a&gt;, but I do not have a lot of individual sites that I have created as a freelancer that are still up and running. This is mostly because I have only done a few sites over the past few years while I have been working most of my time for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason is that I need to get some work up on github. This is similar to the reason above, but also is another way to show my activity and create code samples. The github repos I have worked on have been private, so not much to show. All of the projects I have worked on as a freelancer are private in bitbucket, so again nothing I can show. This gives me code that is public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I need a few things. I need a blog (hence this one) and I need to revise my main freelancer/business site. I want to use the later to sell my services and some products. I have a reseller site that is languishing and that I want to give one last effort to monetize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least there are a few technologies that I want to dig deeper into. This blog for instance uses a static site generator that is built on React and GraphQl. I already know React, but I want to dive deeper and I want to learn GraphQl. Another area I want to explore is the use of a headless WordPress CMS with a React or even a static site (like Gatsby) front end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That about covers it for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[More About Me]]></title><description><![CDATA[My passion is working hands on to craft engaging websites and web applications, but web development is my second career. I graduated college…]]></description><link>https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog//More About Me/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog//More About Me/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 22:55:06 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;My passion is working hands on to craft engaging websites and web applications, but web development is my second career. I graduated college with a chemical engineering degree and in my past life worked for many years in the semiconductor industry as an engineer and manager. My last position in that industry was at a small company that supplied equipment for manufacturing circuits on silicon wafers. The company failed financially during one of the many down cycles in that sector of the economy and I was let go. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I live in Southern California and at the time I lost my job I had a young family to support. My options to remain in the same industry seemed narrow and would have required me to either move out of state or travel abroad extensively. I was determined to stay put where I loved, support my family, and learn something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had always enjoyed working with computers and started my career in web development by selling a software package that included a primitive website builder. I soon realized that most of the small business owners who were my customers had neither the inclination nor the desire to use this software to create their own websites, so I began building the sites for them as a service. But building the websites solely with the site building software I sold was clunky, severely limited, and frustrating. To do a better job and make the websites more functional and attractive I realized that I needed to learn the underlying technology of the web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few years I taught myself how to code websites and web applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I learned how to build and host websites using open source content management systems like WordPress. Eventually I took on a full-time position at a small digital marketing firm where I utilized my new skills and expanded my experience and skill set. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then I have held several other positions in the web and software development  industry. Working in this area has fueled my desire to constantly learn and practice new skills in a fast moving and constantly evolving environment. As far as the work goes I seldom look back with nostalgia on my previous career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may seem like this has all gone great for me, but actually there have been a lot of stops and starts along the way. It turns out that in the long term I have not insulated myself from the ups and downs of the employment market by switching careers. It is just a different game now, but one I enjoy playing a lot more and with many more opportunities locally. I now even have the flexibility of working freelance or remotely from anyplace in the world with an Internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The down side of working in an ever changing and challenging industry is that you always need to be learning and practicing the latest technology. This is great for me because I love to learn and I tend to learn quickly, but at times it can seem overwhelming. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also lots of competition in freelance development. The entry barrier is low for learning the basic skills a developer needs as most of the information is open source and freely available to anyone who has a computer along with the desire and time to learn.  You don’t need a special license and there isn’t a specific college degree you need in order to be successful. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added to that there are many options available to outsource work abroad using cheap freelancing services available on the web.  There are also several new services that make it easier than ever before for small business owners with the inclination to create their own sites. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all just drives me to work especially hard to make my services add value.  &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[First Post]]></title><description><![CDATA[This simple blog is based on the  Gatsby  static site builder. I am starting off by using the starter blog creator and then modifying as I…]]></description><link>https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog//First Post/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://teeehn.github.io/tom-nicolosi-blog//First Post/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 22:46:05 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This simple blog is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gatsbyjs.org/&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;/a&gt; static site builder. I am starting off by using the starter blog creator and then modifying as I please. I expect this to be a hyper-fast loading site!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Gatsby is based on React I am looking forward to extending this site in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>